What do table football, a doll's house and a remote-control car all have in common?
桌上足球、娃娃屋和遥控汽车有什么共同点？
They are all smaller versions of real things.
它们都是真实事物的缩小版。
And humans have long been intrigued by all things miniature.
而人类长久以来一直对一切微型事物着迷。
The Chinese ancient art of nut carving sees artists sculpt intricate designs, including microscopic people, into fruit or nut stones.
中国古代的核雕艺术中，艺术家们在果核上雕刻精美的图案，包括微小的人物。
English author Mary Norton wrote the fictional book series The Borrowers – they are tiny people who live secretly in the walls and floors of a normal-sized house.
英国作家玛丽·诺顿创作了虚构小说系列《借东西的小人》——他们是生活在正常尺寸房屋墙壁和地板缝隙中的微小人物。
And then there are the online channels all about miniature cooking.
此外，还有各种关于微型烹饪的在线频道。
Valarmathi and Rajkumar, who run The Tiny Foods, film tiny versions of traditional Indian dishes being made, set amongst the backdrop of a minuscule village complete with teeny cooking utensils.
经营The Tiny Foods频道的瓦拉玛蒂和拉杰库马尔，拍摄制作传统印度菜肴的微缩版本，背景是一个极小的村庄，配有小小的烹饪器具。
Speaking to the BBC, Valarmathi says she was inspired by her grandmother who 'used to cook in really tiny pots'.
瓦拉玛蒂告诉BBC，她的灵感来自于她的祖母，祖母"过去常常用非常小的锅做饭"。
Similarly, Kate Murdoch, who runs Tiny Kitchen, makes meals cooked on a hob that's powered by a tealight.
同样，经营Tiny Kitchen频道的凯特·默多克，在一个由小蜡烛供能的炉灶上做饭。
Her videos include whisking eggs in a tiny mixing bowl and then cooking omelettes in pans the size of a postage stamp.
她的视频包括在一个微小的搅拌碗里搅打鸡蛋，然后在只有邮票大小的平底锅里煎鸡蛋饼。
And then there's the art world…
还有艺术界……
The miniature artist and photographer Tanaka Tatsuya has been rising to online fame.
微型艺术家兼摄影师田中达也在网上逐渐走红。
He takes everyday small objects and turns them into new fun-size dioramas.
他利用日常小物件，将它们变成新的趣味尺寸的微缩立体模型。
His creations include a face mask resembling lanes in a swimming pool, watermelon mountains and some penguins on an iceberg, which is in fact a bar of soap.
他的作品包括一个类似于游泳池水道的口罩，西瓜山，以及一些在冰山上（实际上是一块肥皂）的企鹅。
So, why do we love small things?
那么，我们为什么喜爱小东西呢？
Simon Garfield, author of In Miniature, says that holding a scaled-down world in our hands, gives us a feeling of control and helps us understand what is too big to envision at full scale, like skyscrapers and railways.
《微缩》一书的作者西蒙·加菲尔德说，将一个按比例缩小的世界捧在手中，给我们一种掌控感，并帮助我们理解那些实物太大而难以想象的事物，比如摩天大楼和铁路。
With models, we can observe, learn and appreciate what we have – with less.
通过模型，我们可以观察、学习并欣赏我们所拥有的——以更小的形式。
He discusses how the fascination may also relate to childhood.
他谈到，这种迷恋也可能与童年有关。
Toy dolls and plastic construction kits make us conquerors of worlds.
玩偶和塑料建筑玩具让我们成为世界的征服者。"
'We may never have such dominion over the world again, unless we continue the play into adulthood.'
我们可能再也不会拥有对世界这样的统治权了，除非我们把这种游戏延续到成年。"
So, just like the worlds of art and literature, why not embrace a little love of miniature?
所以，就像艺术和文学世界一样，为什么不欣然接受对微缩事物的一点热爱呢？